Very
respected Principal, teachers,
parents of the children who have
participated in this helmet distribution ceremony today and
dear
students, first of all,
Sat Sri Akal ji,
yes,
Sikh Le Meto, Ua Aada
Sikh Le Phadi says to write
Punjabi is your mother tongue, peace is my gift to everyone, Punjabi is your mother tongue,
Sat Sri
Akal says to everyone and everyone
say Sat Sri Akal again. Four lights have lit up inside a person.
Son, the first is of love, the second is of
faith, the third is of peace, the fourth is
of hope.
But in the 2nd century, all the lights have gone out. There is
no love, no faith, no
peace. Only one light has lit up,
hope. An attempt is being made to awaken it in you that it was
written in schools that if one person is
taught, the entire society will be educated.
If one person is saved while walking on the road, then there will be less
laughter. If a person is making a
mistake on the road,
try to save him.
Some died, some survived, some survived. So today, the majority of
deaths on our roads during accidents are
among young children between the ages of 16 and 25 and 35.
Children, it is very difficult for a family whose
children become the cause of death during a road accident.
And the parents of the family whose children get into
accidents
also find it very difficult to live
in this society.
So, children, I appeal to you today
that when you have
dinner with your family members this evening,
ask your mom and dad one word, "
Mom and dad, what are our expectations from you?"
Then they will tell you, "We have these
expectations from you, but son, you are ruining those expectations while
driving on the roads."
So, my son, to be
successful in life, you should remember the
teachings of Lord Ram to lead your life in the right way.
You should cultivate the seed and grow into a tree. You should
also cultivate the vine and
grow to the top. You should also cultivate the
entire creation.  So son, stay with Nirmaaz at home,
stay with Nirmaaz at school, while walking on the roads,
be polite, life is never yours,
and children, keep it in your mind
that when we are on the roads, we always
say you first, but we say when we are on the
roads, we will break your legs,
we are very selfish, arrogant, predatory.
So children,
these helmets that you are seeing in front of you are
son, a doctor Chitra ji
from Chandigarh, he is from the Hat Inj Foundation, and children were talking to me in the
traffic
when I was a student, but son,
DSP Ludhiana called me
that Singh ji, I want to give helmets,
I said, I will tell you, the
children said, please do this, I will
send it to you, and children, 1200
helmets came to me, and I called the principal surgeon and
said that whose
We will provide helmets to the parents who drop the child to school, provided that
the parents must have a driving license
because we roam around without a driving
license. We even fire guns
without a license. This is still a crime.
But if
we drive a vehicle on the road without a license, then consider that
you have given a bullet to the raffle. If an
accident happens, the case against the child will be
registered under the BNS. Now, under it, there is a
lot of punishment. And if you, the child, understand this well,
which is up to your age of plus two, then the
child can
never be your guardian for the next 40 years.
This is the age that we often put on the wrong side.
So, children, this
helmet that you are looking at in front of you,
children, when a head injury occurs,
Verma ji talked about the doctor, I will
not do Daksha again.
But
children, even doctors say that if someone
's limb is broken, we can fix it with a plaster,
but if there is a head injury, either
that person dies or, if by God's
grace, they somehow survive, their ability to hear is gone, their
ability to think is gone, and their
ability to see is gone.  And children, a head injury causes a
lot of damage. And
son, we people say that
we are Sardars. Our people believe that we are Sardars.
But son, when a head falls on the road, the road
sees it. The head of the Sardar is that of a Muslim, a Christian, a
Hindu, and the blood that comes out of it is all
red.
These are religious displays.
So, son, the time has passed
when we used to say that whoever gets hurt, knows
who knows the pain. We will consider the blood of someone else spilled on the roads as
our own. Only then
can we remain safe on the roads, otherwise we
cannot remain safe on the roads.  So, my appeal and instruction to those who are going to
give helmets to their children and to those who are going to
give helmets to their parents is
that whenever you drop your child off at school
or pick him up from school,
both the child and the parents should wear a helmet. And if you are
going anywhere on the road, then
tell your child to wear a helmet.  But we would have
taken a helmet, but sometimes we
put it on after seeing the police.
And I will also give an example of this, there is
a village called Dhanthal near Samana, and there was a police
checkpoint there. I was coming from somewhere. After giving a
lecture, I stopped near that NGO, but my
son saw a newly married girl
sitting on the back of a motorcycle, holding a helmet in her hand.
But the policeman in front of the children
said, "Madam, give me your helmet." He put it upside down on his head.
Now listen to the funny story.
We are the ones who protect the child upside down. So, after putting the motorcycle upside down, the child hit the barricade and
fell. They said, "
Sorry, I didn't know, I made a mistake."
Still, they didn't admit it. They had put the helmet on their head upside down.
But, my son, that brave man said, "The
barricade was broken, no problem. You didn't survive."
But if there was a big trolley like this on the road,
you would have fallen into it and said, "It was a
mistake." If you hadn't died on the spot, you would have died.
So, this is why it is the
most difficult thing to live as a human being.
Not by becoming an empty space, not by becoming a priest, not by
becoming God, the path of life is not from now, not from tomorrow, not from
one day, but by
becoming a human being, so son, show humanity on the roads
[Music]
So, children,
when you put on this helmet, you have to put it
under it. If
we keep that strip open or don't
put it on, then show it to all the ladies.
If we don't put it on, then son, it's a motor
vehicle light issue. Okay, if we
keep the strip open, if we don't put the strip on, then
son, then this helmet will be the first thing you see on the
ground during the day. After that, it will be of
no use. But children, the
helmets we buy are cheap.  They say to
avoid police challans, but
children, look at this, look at you, you are showing off by wearing it,
giving a demo in front of people. But
children, when we go to a jewelry store, they
ask, "Tell me how many
carats of jewelry, 24 carats, 22 carats, a good helmet?" They
say, "It's cheap, you can avoid police challans." But,
God forbid, if an accident happens on the road,
children, if we wear a 24 carat bigoted jewelry,
our appearance will become ugly, and our
son will not look good wearing it either. That's why
now I also request all the teachers to
wear helmets if we
come on two-wheelers, and if we come on four-wheelers,
install safety beds.  Let me tell you one more thing,
teachers, if we don't install safety belts, the
safety balloons or air bags worth crores of rupees won't open. If we do
n't install safety belts, number two, if we don't
install safety belts, our vehicle is
going at a speed of 50 kilometers. God forbid, an accident happens, and the injury is
equivalent to falling five meters.
Our car is going at a speed of 100 kmph. An accident happened. We are getting injured
outside.
This is a habit without a
safety belt
and children. Insurance companies do
not give claims now. If you do not wear a safety belt,
they say, prepare a feature. What should we do? If you wear a
safety belt according to the feature, then the
insurance company will give a claim, otherwise the
claim will not be given. No argument, no appeal, no
claim. So, appeal to the family for this.
Understand this yourself. It is not that we do
any work out of fear of the police, we do it out of
fear of the law. It is our
duty, son. If the constitution has given us rights, then it is
our duty to fulfill those rights while
following them.
But son, I would like to make another appeal to you children that
son, whatever your
age, you should vote after 18 years,
you should get a job after 18 years,
but if our family members get married after 18 years,
how much will the child have to be educated? But son,
we start driving like 16-year-olds and 14-year-olds.
This means that we are in the middle of nowhere. So son,
now tell your family
that wearing a helmet is a must, consider it
necessary to protect your head because if you
have a helmet worth 1500 on your head, your head will hurt. If you are
not wearing a helmet, then
in the ICU of the hospital, you all
know how much the bill is,
then paying the ICU bill or
wearing a helmet worth 1500, it is in your hands. So because of this,
son, accidents started happening on the roads every day.
How many people died,
how many heroes were ruined at home, how many crying
souls.  We have forgotten about road safety, we have
left everything to fate, we have
left everything to the administration and
friends. Now think about it. After all,
you also have some responsibilities. After all,
everyone has some responsibilities.
You yourself must shoulder the responsibility. May God
help you on your journey.  Madam Sonia
Chahil ji is sitting here,
come here, Madam ji, come here,
please, the madams who are coming among you,
Sonia Chali, sent me a video.
I will
show it to the children and tell them to become road models.
Madam ji has become a role model and
by becoming a role model, her life has been saved,
she is giving a message to the next generation.  So
I have a recording but I will
not listen to the recording because I am present here. They will
tell you live how I had an
accident and how I survived. Okay,
son, once you have
come to my senses, Madam, a big round of applause for them.
Now, children, if you travel from the last bench to the next bench, the trunk will
open. If the street market guru
stands in the way,
Sentences are like a night of words, may
his grace be like a rain of words.
In childhood, my mother gave me a pen and paper. May
his grace be like a rain of words. That is how
words are showered. My son, if the
storm of historical masters stands before you,
I appeal to you, Madam, to
come and say two words about your accident. May the
children be happy,
my son.